荣誉出品
最专业冰火字幕
专注GOT剧集
翻译   夜俱
翻译   北落师门
翻译   陌客之子
君临 King's Landing
翻译   拉拉兄控凯冯
红堡
Red Keep
校对   pksunking
校对   盗墓奸尸
恐怖堡 Dreadfort
时间轴   poplar
临冬城
Winterfell
后期    窝鹏偏逢连夜
后期    加文·维斯特林
后期    Jeremy
监制    临冬城的狮子   托曼
策划    baozhenyuawabi
特别顾问   屈畅(ccxx)@史诗图书
绝境长城 the Wall
最专业的华语冰火资料站：                         中文维基
http://zh.asoiaf.wikia.com/
百度冰与火之歌贴吧  &  百度权力的游戏贴吧    联合出品
史诗图书  正统奇幻的圣殿
布拉佛斯
Braavos
弥林
Meereen
根据长篇小说
《冰与火之歌》 改编
原著  乔治·R·R·马丁
衣柜字幕组
更多冰火资讯
请扫码关注“黑城堡”微信平台
微信号：HEICHENGBAO
第六集  The Laws of Gods and Men
国法家法
史坦尼斯·拜拉席恩
狭海中的王
戴佛斯·席渥斯
“洋葱骑士” 史坦尼斯的首相
布拉佛斯：隐秘海湾中数百座岛屿组成的石头城市，被一座岛屿环绕，仅留一个出口，被巨大的泰坦巨人雕像保护。
泰坦巨人不仅是地标、灯塔，还是防御堡垒，两旁有战斗堡垒和被称作兵工厂的巨大船坞
陛下 如果您想坐坐 我确信——
Your Grace, if you'd like to sit, I'm sure that--
我们中午就到这儿了
We've been here since midday.
我常常发现 东方人的时间观念和我们不同
Easterners have a difference sense of time, I've often found.
有次 也是在布拉佛斯 我等候萨拉多·桑恩
Once I was waiting for Salladhor Saan here in Braavos.
我们打算“运走”
Together, we were going to run
三船最好的——
three shiploads of the finest--
铁金库：布拉佛斯最重要的银行，非常富有并经常借钱给外人。它在收取债务时拥有可怕的声誉，
当亲王或国王拖欠他们的债务或不尊重合同时，叛王和叛军将会获得经济援助以推翻统治。
泰楚·奈斯托斯
铁金库代表
欢迎来到铁金库
Welcome to the Iron Bank.
请坐
Please, sit.
不知我们能为您做些什么 史坦尼斯大人？
What can we do for you, Lord Stannis?
这是拜拉席恩家族的史坦尼斯
This is Stannis of the House Baratheon,
安达尔人和先民的国王
King of the Andals and the First Men,
七大王国的统治者与全境守护者
Lord of the Seven Kingdoms and Protector of the Realm.
铁王座目前属于
The Iron Throne is currently occupied
拜拉席恩家族的托曼
by Tommen of the House Baratheon,
安达尔人和先民的国王
King of the Andals and the First Men,
七大王国的统治者与全境守护者
Lord of the Seven Kingdoms and Protector of the Realm.
他与我毫无血脉关系
He shares no blood with me.
他乃是乱伦所生的私生子
He is a bastard born of incest.
这点和他哥哥一个样
As was his brother before him.
是哦 我们听过这故事
Yes, we have heard this story.
这不是故事 这是真相
It's not a story. It's the truth.
可国王的外公却讲了个不同的故事
The king's grandfather tells a different story.
故事里 一个嫉妒的叔叔
A story about a jealous uncle
为了从正统国王手中篡夺王位
whose attempts to usurp the throne from the rightful king
不惜让七大王国血流遍地 耗尽钱财
cost the Seven Kingdoms dearly in blood and gold.
是你们借给他的钱财
Gold you loaned him.
现在你觉得你的血脉给了你借钱的理由？
And you feel your blood gives you a claim on our gold?
比任何在世的人理由都充分
More than any man living.
在狭海那一边 你的账簿里满是
Across the Narrow Sea, your books are filled
“篡夺者” “疯子”之类的词语
with words like "usurper" and "madman"
也有“血统纯正”
and "blood right."
而在这里 我们的账簿里都是些数字
Here, our books are filled with numbers.
我们更喜欢他们讲的故事
We prefer the stories they tell.
更直白
More plain.
不那么充满歧义
Less open to interpretation.
还有多少战士忠于你？
How many fighting men remain loyal to you?
4,000.
你还有多少艘船？
And how many ships do you have?
当然是指还能漂着的船 戴佛斯爵士
The ones still afloat, Ser Davos,
不包括沉在黑水河底下的
not at the bottom of Blackwater Bay.
32.
龙石岛能出产多少
And how much wheat and barley and beef
小麦 大麦 牛肉和猪肉
and pork do you produce on Dragonstone
来供养您那32艘船上的4000勇士？
to feed your 4,000 men on your 32 ships?
没有
None.
那么您应该明白 为什么从我们的角度来看
You can see why these numbers seem unlikely to add up
这些数字不太可能推导出一个美好的结果
to a happy ending from our perspective.
我很抱歉我们必须恭恭敬敬地
I'm afraid we must respectfully
拒绝您的要求
decline your request.
但我们对您的赏光表示最衷心的感谢
But we thank you for paying us the honor of your visit.
大人
My lord.
我可不是什么大人 戴佛斯·席渥斯爵士
I'm not a lord, Ser Davos Seaworth.
当然您在这儿也不是什么爵士
You would not be either here.
在布拉佛斯
In Braavos,
我们可不会给小偷奖励什么头衔
thieves are not rewarded with titles.
噢 严格地说 我不干偷窃的勾当
Well, strictly speaking, I didn't do the thieving.
那是海盗的活计
That would be the pirates.
我只是把他们偷来的东西从一个地方搬到另一个地方
I just moved what they stole from one place to another.
而这个 是史坦尼斯国王
This is the payment that was demanded
让我为自己的罪行付出的代价
by King Stannis for my crimes.
我认为那是一个公正的裁决
I consider it an honest accounting.
他是个公正的人 也是你们最好的机会
He's an honest man and he's your best chance
能让你们收回在维斯特洛的坏账
to get back the money you've sunk into Westeros.
我想那一定是笔大数目 战争总是耗费钱财的
Which is a lot, I imagine. Wars are expensive.
战争已然结束
The war is over.
只要史坦尼斯国王还活着，战争就没有结束
As long as Stannis lives, the war is not over.
谁在君临握有实权？
Who's the real power in King's Landing?
- 戴佛斯爵士…… - 回答我
- Ser Davos... - Humor me.
- 泰温·兰尼斯特 - 泰温·兰尼斯特多大了？
- Tywin Lannister. - How old is Tywin Lannister?
- 67  - 67岁了 那他死后 何人统治？
- 67. - 67. And when he dies, who's in command?
一个半大孩子
A half-grown boy,
还是乱伦的产物
the product of incest?
或是瑟曦·兰尼斯特 一个人人厌恶的太后
Cersei Lannister, a queen whose people despise her?
还是詹姆·兰尼斯特 因为杀死
Jaime Lannister, a man best known for killing the king
自己宣誓要保护的君主而闻名的人？
he was sworn to protect?
一旦泰温死了 还有谁能给你还债？
When Tywin's gone, who do you back?
那是以后的问题了
That is a problem for another time.
恕我直言 这是当下的问题
Begging your pardon, I think it's a problem for now.
这儿 站着维斯特洛仅存的一位可靠的领主
There's only one reliable leader left in Westeros.
史坦尼斯
Stannis.
他有与生俱来的继承权
He's got the birthright.
他正当壮年
He's in his prime.
身经战争的洗礼
He's a tried and tested battle commander.
他绝不空谈什么给人回报
And he doesn't just talk about paying people back,
而是身体力行
he does it.
哨兵看见有艘海盗船驶向他们
The lookout sees a pirate ship sailing their way.
船长对他的大副喊道
The captain shouts to his first mate,
“把我的红衬衫拿来！”
"Bring me my red shirt."
萨拉多·桑恩
海盗
大副拿来了红衬衫 船长穿上它
The first mate brings the red shirt and the captain puts it on.
当海盗试图登船
And when the pirates try to board,
这个勇敢的船长带着他的船员们取得了胜利
the brave captain leads his men to victory.
几天后 哨兵又开始喊叫
A few days later, the lookout screams,
“有两艘海盗船！”
"Two pirate ships!"
船员们像老鼠一样吓得发抖
The crew is shivering like scared mice.
但英勇的船长再一次喊道
But the courageous captain hollers,
“把我的红衬衫拿来！”
"Bring me my red shirt!"
战斗平息后 大副问道
After the battle, the first mate asks,
“船长 为什么你战斗前都要穿你的红衬衫？”
"Captain, why do you call for your red shirt before battle?"
船长答道
The captain replies,
“这样就算我被刀捅了 你们也看不到我流血”
"So that if I am stabbed, you will not see me bleed."
第二天早晨哨兵又开始呼喊
The next morning the lookout screams,
“10艘海盗船！
"10 pirate ships!
我们被包围了！”
We are surrounded!"
船员们一片沉默
The crew goes silent.
他们看向那勇敢的船长
They all look to their brave captain,
等着他一贯的命令
waiting for his usual command.
死水一般的寂静 船长大吼
Calm as ever, the captain bellows...
“把我的屎黄色裤子拿来！”
"Bring me my brown pants!"
你觉得她们遇到的哪个海盗不和她讲这个笑话？
You think they ever met a pirate who didn't tell them that joke?
戴佛斯
Davos.
我听说你在龙石岛的地牢里烂掉了
I heard you were rotting in a dungeon in Dragonstone.
只烂了一半
Only half rotted.
来吧 朋友 加入我们 来吧
Join us, my friend. Join us.
这是劳拉
This is Lhara.
- 而这位是—— - 我才是劳拉
- And this is-- - I am Lhara.
她是个艺术家 这一位 真的
She's an artist, this one, truly.
恐怕没时间了 我们日出就得起航
No time, I'm afraid. We sail at sunrise.
我们？
We?
你 我——我们
You, me-- we.
我以前还以为这人爱我呢
Once I thought this man loved me.
现在我知道他根本没把我当回事儿
Now I know he despises me.
他竟然想让我孤苦伶仃 身上一个子儿没有地死在某个冷冰冰——
He wants to see me die poor and alone on some cold--
你又不是一个人
You won't be alone.
而且绝不会没钱可拿
And you won't be poor.
我已经在你家里留了一箱金器
There's a chest of the good stuff left back at your house.
给了你老婆
I gave it to your wife.
朋友啊 你绝对不是我朋友
You're not my friend, my friend.
我们日出见
I'll see you at sunrise.
“我以满月为限
"I give you until the full moon
命令所有铁渣滓统统滚出北境
to order all ironborn scum out of the North
回到你们称之为家的粘着屎的石头上
and back to those shit-stained rocks you call home.
满月后的第一个晚上
On the first night of the full moon,
我会狩捕还在我们领土上的每一个岛民
I will hunt down every islander still on our lands
并将其活活剥皮
and flay them living,
就像我活剥在临冬城找到的
the way I flayed the 20 ironborn scum
亚拉·葛雷乔伊
席恩·葛雷乔伊的姐姐
20个铁渣滓那样
I found at Winterfell.
盒子里我放了份特别的礼物
In the box you'll find a special gift--
席恩最喜欢的玩具
Theon's favorite toy.
拉姆斯·雪诺
卢斯·波顿的私生子
当我将它拿走时 席恩哭了
He cried when I took it away from him.
滚出北境 不然还会有更多的盒子
Leave the North now or more boxes will follow
里面装着更多的席恩
with more Theon.
落款 拉姆斯•雪诺
Signed Ramsay Snow,
卢斯•波顿  恐怖堡领主
natural born son of Roose Bolton,
兼北境守护的
Lord of the Dreadfort
亲生儿子”
and Warden of the North."
就是这样！
Yes!
他们活剥了我们的国民
They skinned our countrymen
他们还阉了我弟弟
and they mutilated my brother,
你们的王子
your prince.
你们的王子！
Your prince.
他们对他所做的每一件事
Everything they've done to him,
也是在对你们这么做
they've also done to you.
就是这样！ 就是这样！
Yes! Yes!
只要他们能伤害我们的王子却不受惩罚
As long as they can hurt our prince with impunity,
那铁种这个词就毫无意义
the word ironborn means nothing.
往左
Go left.
- 席恩·葛雷乔伊 - 我不知道——
- Theon Greyjoy. - I don't know--
我来这儿是找席恩·葛雷乔伊
I'm here for Theon Greyjoy.
带我去地牢
Take me to the dungeons.
他不在地牢
He's not in the dungeons.
- 右边最后一个笼子 - 谢了
- Last cage on the right. - Thank you.
这里！
This way!
“臭佬”
席恩·葛雷乔伊
我们回家
We're going home.
不！
No!
没事了 是我 亚拉
It's all right. It's me, Yara.
你骗不了我
You can't trick me.
跟他说 跟他说你骗不了我
Tell him. Tell him you couldn't trick me.
席恩 我没骗你 我是来救你的
I'm not tricking you, Theon. I'm saving you.
我不是席恩！我是臭佬！
Not Theon! Reek!
- 臭佬！我是臭佬！ - 他们来了
- Reek! My name is Reek! -  They're here.
在这被堵住 我们就死定了
If they catch us in here, we're trapped.
帮我带走他
Help me with him.
不 不行
No, you can't!
- 不行！ - 你是席恩·葛雷乔伊
- You can't! - You're Theon Greyjoy.
不 我不相信你！我知道我是谁！
No, I don't believe her! I know who I am!
我是臭佬！忠诚的臭佬！
I'm Reek! Reek! Loyal Reek!
乖乖的臭佬！我永远是臭佬！
Good Reek! I've always been Reek!
今晚真是妙不可言
This is turning into a lovely evening.
我是臭佬！
I'm Reek!
忠诚的臭佬！
Loyal Reek!
啊！席恩！
Aah! Theon!
把我弟弟还给我 你的人就不必再为此丧命
Give me my brother and no more of your men will die.
你比这货更有种
You've got bigger balls than he ever did.
不过光是有种可不够……
But with those big balls of yours...
咱们看看你能跑多快？
how fast can you run?
立刻回船上
Make for the ship, now.
你弟弟怎么办
But your brother.
我弟弟已经死了
My brother is dead.
我有个惊喜给你
I have a treat for you.
一个奖励
A reward.
奖励？
Reward?
是的 臭佬
Yes, Reek.
那些玩意儿夜里来
Those creatures who came in the night,
想要带你走
they wanted to take you away.
而你没让他们得逞
And you didn't let them.
你很忠诚
You remained loyal.
我——我不想他们带我走
I-- I didn't want them to take me.
我很害怕
I was so scared.
- 我不想他们—— - 是的 是的 臭佬
- I didn't want them-- - Yes, yes, Reek.
浴缸在那儿
It's a bath.
为你准备的
For you.
把那些破烂脱了
Remove those rags.
快点
Now.
还有裤子呢 臭佬
The britches, too, Reek.
也脱了
Take them off.
臭佬 你爱我吗？
Do you love me, Reek?
当然 大人 当然
Yes, of course, my lord.
很好
Good.
那么你得帮我做点事
Because I need you to do something for me.
很重要的事
Something very important.
你瞧 现在有座城堡
There's a castle, you see.
被坏人霸占着
Some bad men hold this castle.
你得帮我把城堡抢回来
I need your help to take this castle back.
但我怎么——
But how can--
你得演出好戏
I need you to play a role.
假扮别人
To pretend to be someone you're not.
假扮谁？
Pretend to be who?
席恩·葛雷乔伊
Theon Greyjoy.
你面前的是弥林的统治者
安达尔人和先民的女王
大草原上的卡丽熙
镣铐破除者
“不焚者” “龙之母”
坦格利安家族的“风暴降生”
丹妮莉丝一世
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安
“风暴降生” 龙之母
巴利斯坦·赛尔弥
女王铁卫 “无畏的”
乔拉·莫尔蒙
“大熊”
朋友 别害怕
弥桑黛
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安的侍女
女王叫你上前说话
他是个牧羊人
He is a goatherd.
他说他曾经为您祝福，祝您战胜那些奴隶主
He says he prayed for your victory against the slave masters.
我感谢他的祝福
I thank him for his prayers.
他说 是您的龙干的
It was your dragons, he says.
他们今早袭击了他的羊群
They came this morning for his flock.
他说他不想冒犯陛下
He hopes he has not offended Your Grace,
可是他现在一无所有了
but now he has nothing.
告诉他 我非常同情他的遭遇
Tell this man I am sorry for his hardship.
我不能还给他山羊
I cannot bring back his goats,
但我会付给他三倍价值的赔偿
but I will see he is paid their value three times over.
叫下一个上来
Send the next one in.
高贵的西茨达拉•佐•洛拉克请求与女王进行谈话
高贵的西茨达拉•佐•洛拉克本人可以与我进行谈话
丹妮莉丝女王
Queen Daenerys.
关于您美貌的传闻丝毫没有夸张
Tales of your beauty were not exaggerated.
谢谢
I thank you.
我来自弥林最古老最高贵的家族之一
Mine is one of the oldest and proudest families in Meereen.
接见你是我的荣幸
Then it is my honor to receive you.
家父是弥林最有威望最受爱戴的市民
My father, one of Meereen's most respected
负责监管、修复和维护
and beloved citizens, oversaw the restoration
弥林最宏伟最有代表性的建筑
and maintenance of its greatest landmarks.
其中就包括这些金字塔
This pyramid included.
为此致上我的敬意
For that, he has my gratitude.
我希望能有幸见到他
I should be honored to meet him.
陛下 您已经见过了
You have, Your Grace.
他被您钉在十字架上
You crucified him.
我祝您永远不会看到您的家人
I pray you'll never live to see
被如此残忍地虐待
a member of your family treated so cruelly.
令尊把无辜的孩童钉死在十字架上
Your father crucified innocent children.
家父公开反对这种做法
My father spoke out against crucifying those children.
他说这是罪恶的行径 但是孤掌难鸣
He decried it as a criminal act, but was overruled.
用罪行来惩罚罪行是否公正呢？
Is it justice to answer one crime with another?
我很遗憾你失去了父亲
I am sorry you no longer have a father,
但是伟主大人们是罪有应得
but my treatment of the masters was no crime.
你最好给我记住这一点
You'd be wise to remember that.
此事已成定局
What's done is done.
您是女王 而我是弥林的仆从
You are the queen and I am a servant of Meereen.
我不愿意看到弥林的传统被废除
A servant who does not wish to see its traditions eradicated.
你在说哪项传统？
And what traditions do you speak of?
葬礼的传统
The tradition of funeral rite.
在圣恩神庙举行体面的葬礼
Proper burial in the Temple of the Graces.
家父和162位弥林贵族
My father and 162 noble Meereenese
仍然被钉在木桩上
are still nailed to those posts,
被秃鹰啄食 被烈日暴晒
carrion for vultures, rotting in the sun.
陛下 我恳求您下令放下这些人
Your Grace, I ask that you order these men taken down
以便体面地下葬
so that they might receive proper burials.
那么 弥林贵族们钉在十字架上的奴隶孩子们怎么办？
And what of the slave children these noble Meereenese crucified?
他们也在烈日下暴晒
They were rotting in the sun as well.
你会恳求我也给他们体面下葬的权利吗？
Would you have begged me for their right to a proper burial?
陛下 我不是在为伟主大人们辩护
Your Grace, I cannot defend the actions of the masters.
我只是一个深爱着父亲的儿子
I can only speak to you as a son who loved his father.
我请求您放他下来
Let me take his body down.
允许我带他到神庙
Let me have him brought to the temple
办理高贵的丧仪
and buried with dignity
这样他在彼岸才能寻得安宁
so that he might find peace in the next world.
西茨达拉•佐•洛拉克 你可以埋葬你的父亲
Bury your father, Hizdahr zo Loraq.
感谢您 陛下
Thank you, my queen.
还有多少？
How many more?
回陛下 还有212个人请求觐见
There are 212 supplicants waiting, Your Grace.
212？
212?
传唤下一个
Send the next one in.
奥柏伦·马泰尔
“红毒蛇” 多恩亲王
开会非得这么早吗？
These meetings aren't always going to be this early, are they?
我昨晚熬得挺晚
I was up late last night.
是不是说我现在也是个什么大臣了？
So, does this mean I am a master of something now?
财政大臣？海政大臣？
Coins, ships?
泰温大人和我已经决定
Lord Tywin and I already determined
派席尔
大学士
梅斯·提利尔
高庭公爵 玛格丽·提利尔之父
由我来担任海政大臣 在你——
that I shall be the Master of Ships long before you--
泰温大人 很荣幸
Lord Tywin, it's a great honor
忝列御前会议之席 我——
to have been granted a seat on this council. I--
审判在下午进行
The trial begins this afternoon.
只有上午有点时间来处理事务
We only have the morning for affairs of state.
可以开始了么？
Shall we begin?
大人 有人在河间地
Sandor Clegane has been spotted
看到了桑铎•克里冈
in the Riverlands, my lord.
瑟曦·兰尼斯特
太后
懦夫 叛徒
A coward and a traitor.
我的小小鸟儿报告说猎狗杀了我们五个士兵
My birds tell me the Hound slaughtered five of our soldiers.
瓦里斯
“八爪蜘蛛” 情报总管
我认为他肯定说了“操他妈的国王”这种话
I believe the phrase "fuck the king" was uttered.
简直无礼
Disgraceful.
要出多少钱才能让普通士兵
What would it take to make the common soldier
蠢到去猎狗身上碰运气？
stupid enough to try his luck with the Hound?
10枚银鹿应该够丰厚了
10 silver stags seems a generous bounty.
泰温·兰尼斯特
凯岩城公爵 国王之手
100枚 还有呢？
Make it 100. What else?
大人 来自东方的情报越来越多了
More whispers from the east, my lord.
坦格利安孤女？
The Targaryen girl?
丹妮莉丝攻占了弥林
Daenerys has taken up residence in Meereen.
她征服了那里 以女王的身份统治那里
She has conquered the city and rules as its queen.
她哪来的兵？
Conquered with what?
她有一支无垢者大军 陛下
She commands an army of Unsullied, my queen.
八千多人
Some 8,000 strong.
她还有一支雇佣军——
She has a company of sellswords--
次子团
the Second Sons.
他有两位骑士辅佐——
She has two knights advising her--
乔拉·莫尔蒙和巴利斯坦·赛尔弥
Jorah Mormont and Barristan Selmy.
另外 她有三头龙
And she has three dragons.
龙宝宝罢了
Baby dragons.
每年都在长大啊 陛下
Larger every year, Your Grace.
莫尔蒙是我们的卧底
Mormont is spying on her for us.
已经不是了 看来他现在全心效忠于她
No longer. He appears to be fully devoted to her.
至于巴利斯坦爵士
As for Ser Barristan, it would seem
看来他比我们预想
he took his dismissal from the Kingsguard
更难接受自己被开除出御林铁卫的事实
a bit harder than anticipated.
他太老了
He's an old man.
保护不了我的儿子
He wasn't fit to protect my son.
乔佛里的死又不是因为他的失职
Joffrey didn't die on his watch.
开除他既无礼又愚蠢
Dismissing him was as insulting as it was stupid.
别跟我说你正在担心半个世界以外的一个小丫头
Don't tell me you're worried about a child halfway across the world.
这个小丫头有两名善战的勇士辅佐
A child with two seasoned warriors counseling her
帐下还有一支劲旅 陛下
and a powerful army at her back, Your Grace.
瓦里斯大人说得对
Lord Varys is right.
我曾在厄斯索斯亲眼见过无垢者
I have been to Essos and seen the Unsullied firsthand.
他们在战场上十分勇猛
They are very impressive on the battlefield.
床上稍微差点
Less so in the bedroom.
三百年来 赢得战争的不是龙
Dragons haven't won a war in 300 years.
而是军队
Armies win them all the time.
她的问题必须被处理妥当
She must be dealt with.
怎么处理呢 大人？
How, my lord?
付诸武力？
By force?
如果真到了那个地步的话 武力是最终手段
Eventually, if it comes to that.
你的小小鸟能渗透到弥林吗？
Can your little birds find their way into Meereen?
当然可以 首相大人
Most certainly, my Lord Hand.
嗯 提利尔大人 帮我个忙
Mmm. Lord Tyrell, be a good man.
把羽毛笔和纸递给我
Fetch my quill and paper.
奥柏伦亲王
Prince Oberyn.
瓦里斯大人……
Lord Varys...
叫我瓦里斯就好 实际上我不是贵族
Only Varys. I'm not actually a nobleman.
任何人都没有义务称我为大人
No one is under obligation to call me lord.
但是每个人都这样做
And yet everyone does.
你好像对无垢者了解颇深啊
You seem quite knowledgeable about the Unsullied.
你在厄索斯待过很久吗？
Did you spend much time in Essos?
待过五年
Five years.
能否问一下为什么？
May I ask why?
这世界广阔而美丽
'Tis a big and beautiful world.
但大多数人从生到死
Most of us live and die
只能窝在自己出生的那个小角落
in the same corner where we were born
却无缘见识别处的风景
and never get to see any of it.
我不想成为这样的人
I don't want to be most of us.
不是所有人都是亲王
Most of us aren't princes.
你来自厄索斯
You are from Essos.
哪儿？里斯？
Where? Lys?
我能分辨人们的口音
I have an ear for accents.
我早就没有口音了
I've lost my accent entirely.
但我仍旧能分辨得出
I have an ear for that as well.
你是怎么来到这儿的？
How did you get here?
这是个很长的故事
It's a long story.
也是你不愿告诉别人的故事
One you don't like telling people.
得是我信任的人才行
People I trust.
你应该去妓院 见见我的情妇艾拉莉亚
My paramour Ellaria, she would find you very interesting.
她会觉得你非常有趣
You should come to the brothel and meet her.
我们自己带了的酒 不是这里的那些泔水
We brought our own wine, not the swill they serve here.
我们还买了几个可爱的男孩 不过……
We have some lovely boys on retainer, but...
你之前喜欢男孩吗？
You did like boys before?
真的？
Really?
那么是女孩咯？ 哦
Girls? Hmm.
我压根没猜到 希望没有冒犯到你
I hope you won't be offended when I say I never would have guessed.
不会的
Not at all.
但我也从未对女孩感兴趣过
But I was never interested in girls, either.
- 那你到底喜欢什么？ - 什么都不喜欢
- What then? -  Nothing.
每个人都会有感兴趣的事
Everybody is interested in something.
但我没有
Not me.
我见识过欲望对人的影响
When I see what desire does to people,
对国家的影响
what it's done to this country,
我很高兴我不会被它左右
I am very glad to have no part in it.
况且 欲望的缺失
Besides, the absence of desire
让我有更多精力追寻其他事情
leaves one free to pursue other things.
比如说？
Such as?
提利昂·兰尼斯特
“小恶魔”
詹姆·兰尼斯特
“弑君者”  御林铁卫队长
让我猜猜 我被赦免了
Let me guess, I've been pardoned.
真要这么做？
Really?
是父亲的命令
Father's orders.
好吧 可不能让父亲失望
Well, we mustn't disappoint Father.
弑君者！
Kingslayer!
托曼·拜拉席恩
铁王座上的王
玛格丽·提利尔
乔佛里·拜拉席恩的遗孀
托曼·拜拉席恩的未婚妻
洛拉斯·提利尔
“百花骑士”
我 拜拉席恩家族的
I, Tommen of the House Baratheon,
托曼一世
First of my Name,
安达尔人和先民的国王
King of the Andals and the First Men,
暨七大王国的统治者
and Lord of the Seven Kingdoms,
于此审判期间 将吾之位置
do hereby recuse myself from this trial.
交于兰尼斯特家族的泰温 国王之手
Tywin of the House Lannister, Hand of the King,
全境守护者 由其代行法官职务
Protector of the Realm, will sit as judge in my stead.
马泰尔家族的奥柏伦亲王和
And with him Prince Oberyn of the House Martell
提利尔家族的梅斯大人为之辅弼
and Lord Mace of the House Tyrell.
若罪名成立
And if found guilty...
愿诸神惩处
may the gods punish the accused.
兰尼斯特家族的提利昂
Tyrion of the House Lannister,
你被摄政太后指控弑君
you stand accused by the Queen Regent of regicide.
是你杀害了乔佛里国王吗？
Did you kill King Joffrey?
不是
No.
是你妻子珊莎女士干的吗？
Did your wife, the Lady Sansa?
据我所知不是
Not that I know of.
那你认为他是怎么死的？
How would you say he died, then?
他是被鸽子馅饼噎死的
Choked on his pigeon pie.
依你之见 莫非是厨师所为？
So you would blame the bakers?
要么是他们 要么是鸽子 反正怪不到我头上
Or the pigeons. Just leave me out of it.
传召第一位证人觐见
The crown may call its first witness.
当我们把乔佛里国王从暴民中安全救出时
Once we'd got King Joffrey safely away
小恶魔过来指责他
from the mob, the Imp rounded on him.
扇了国王一耳光
He slapped the king across the face
还说他是残暴的蠢蛋
and called him a vicious idiot and a fool.
这不是小恶魔第一次威胁乔佛里了
It wasn't the first time the Imp threatened Joffrey.
马林·特兰
御林铁卫
就在这个王座厅
Right here in this throne room,
他走上台阶 称我们的国王是个笨蛋
he marched up those steps and called our king a halfwit.
把陛下与疯王相提并论
Compared His Grace to the Mad King
并暗示陛下将会有同样的下场
and suggested he'd meet the same fate.
而当我出言维护国王时
And when I spoke in the king's defense,
他威胁要杀掉我
he threatened to have me killed.
哦 那你怎么不说乔佛里都干了什么？
Oh, why don't you tell them what Joffrey was doing?
- 安静 - 他拿一把装填好的十字弓对着珊莎·史塔克
- Silence. - Pointing a loaded crossbow at Sansa Stark
而你则撕掉她的衣服 还殴打她
while you tore at her clothes and beat her.
安静！
Silence!
除非我要求 否则你不得说话
You will not speak unless called upon.
你可以退下了 马林爵士
You're dismissed, Ser Meryn.
蛇蜥毒
Basilisk venom,
寡妇之血
widow's blood,
附子草
wolfsbane,
夜影之水精华
essence of nightshade,
甜睡花
sweetsleep,
里斯之泪
tears of Lys,
鬼舞草……
demon's dance...
瞎眼毒——
blind eye--
大学士 我觉得你已经说明你的重点了
I think you have made your point, Grand Maester.
你存了很多的毒药
You have a lot of poison in your store.
那是以前 奥柏伦亲王
Had, Prince Oberyn.
我的储藏早已被洗劫一空了
My stores were plundered.
被谁？
By whom?
被告人 提利昂·兰尼斯特
By the accused, Tyrion Lannister,
在他以莫须有的罪名将我囚禁之后
after he had me wrongfully imprisoned.
大学士
Grand Maester,
你查验过乔佛里国王的尸体
you examined King Joffrey's corpse.
他是被毒杀的 这一点毫无疑问？
Was it without question poison that killed him?
毫无疑问
Without question.
这是在国王的弄臣唐托斯·霍拉德
This was found on the body of Dontos Hollard,
的尸体上发现的
the king's fool.
人们最后看到他时 他正在怂恿被告人之妻
He was last seen spiriting Sansa Stark,
珊莎·史塔克逃离宴会
the wife of the accused, away from the feast.
而她在婚礼当天
She wore this necklace
正是戴着这条项链
the day of the wedding.
在其中发现了毒药残渣
Residue of a most rare
一味极其罕见而恐怖的毒药
and terrible poison was found inside.
这味毒药是你被盗的储藏中的吗？
Was this one of the poisons stolen from your store?
是的 叫扼死者
It was. The Strangler.
这毒药在七大王国非常少见
A poison few in the Seven Kingdoms possess.
它被用来杀死诸神赐给这片土地的
And used to strike down the most noble child
最高贵的孩子
the gods ever put on this good earth.
“总有一天
"I will hurt you for this.
当你自以为平安快活时
A day will come when you think you are safe and happy
喜乐会在嘴里化为灰烬
and your joy will turn to ashes in your mouth
到那时候 你会明白债已偿还”
and you will know the debt is paid."
你的亲弟弟这么对你说的？
Your own brother said this to you?
就在黑水河之战不久前
Shortly before the Battle of Blackwater Bay.
我因他将乔佛里推上前线的计划与他对峙
I confronted him about his plans to put Joffrey on the front lines.
后来 当进攻来临时
As it turned out, when the attack came,
小乔坚持要留在城墙上
Joff insisted on remaining at the battlements.
他坚信他的出现能鼓舞士气
He believed his presence would inspire the troops.
提利昂说
Tyrion said,
“你会明白债已偿还”
"And you will know the debt is paid."
什么债？
What debt?
我发现他竟然在首相塔里
I discovered he'd been keeping whores
偷偷养了个妓女
in the Tower of the Hand.
而我早要求过他
I asked him to confine his salacious acts
此等淫荡恶习不应带出妓院
to the brothel where such behavior belongs.
他怀恨在心
He wasn't pleased.
谢谢你 陛下
Thank you, Your Grace,
谢谢你作证的勇气
for the courage of your testimony.
你还准确的记得威胁的内容？
Do you remember the precise nature of this threat?
我记得很清楚 大人
I'm afraid I do, my lord.
他说 “那你更应该对我礼貌一些
He said, "Perhaps you should speak more softly to me, then.
怪物是很危险的
Monsters are dangerous
国王和蚊蝇在他眼里都一样”
and just now kings are dying like flies."
他是在御前会议上对你这么说的？
And he said this to you at a meeting of the small council?
是的
Yes.
在我们得知罗柏·史塔克的死讯之后
After we received word of Robb Stark's death.
他似乎对此并不感到高兴
He didn't seem gladdened by the news.
或许他与珊莎·史塔克的婚姻
Perhaps his marriage to Sansa Stark
使他对北境的事业更加同情
had made him more sympathetic to the northern cause.
你可以退下了 瓦里斯大人
You're excused, Lord Varys.
父亲 我可以问这位证人一个问题吗？
Father, may I ask the witness one question?
只有一个
One.
你曾说
You once said
如果没有我 这座城市将必然面临毁灭
that without me, this city would have faced certain defeat.
你说过 历史永远不会提及我的名字
You said the histories would never mention me,
但你不会忘记我
but you would not forget.
你忘了吗 瓦里斯大人？
Have you forgotten, Lord Varys?
真是不幸 大人
Sadly, my lord,
我没忘记过任何事情
I never forget a thing.
现在休庭
We will adjourn for now.
一小时后鸣钟继续
Toll the bells in an hour's time.
退场！
Clear the court!
你要判自己的儿子死罪吗？
You'd condemn your own son to death?
我谁也没判 审判还没结束
I've condemned no one. The trial is not over.
这不是什么审判 这是一出闹剧
This isn't a trial. It's a farce.
瑟曦操纵了一切 你知道的
Cersei has manipulated everything and you know it.
我什么都不知道
I know nothing of the sort.
- 你一直讨厌提利昂 - 他杀了他的国王
- You've always hated Tyrion. - He killed his king.
我也一样
As did I.
你知道疯王最后给我的命令是什么吗？
Do you know the last order the Mad King gave me?
他要我献上你的脑袋
To bring him your head.
我救了你一命是为了让你来谋害我的弟弟吗？
I saved your life so you could murder my brother?
- 那不是谋害 是正义  - 正义？
- It won't be murder. It'll be justice. - Justice?
我恪守誓言履行御前首相的职责
I'm performing my sworn duty as Hand of the King.
若提利昂被认定有罪 他将受的刑罚将量罪而定
If Tyrion is found guilty, he will be punished accordingly.
- 他会被处死 -不 他将受应得之刑
- He'll be executed. - No, he'll be punished accordingly.
你曾经说过代代延续的是家族
Once you said family is what lives on.
只有家族
All that lives on.
你说你的王朝将存续千年
You told me about a dynasty that would last 1,000 years.
如果提利昂死了你的王朝要怎么办？
What happens to your dynasty when Tyrion dies?
我是御林铁卫
I'm a Kingsguard,
誓言让我无法延续家族血脉
forbidden by oath to carry on the family line.
我很了解你的誓言
I'm well aware of your oath.
那你的姓氏怎么传承？
What happens to your name?
谁将带着狮子的旗帜来加入以后的战斗？
Who carries the lion banner into future battles?
你的外甥们？
Your nephews?
蓝塞尔·兰尼斯特？
Lancel Lannister?
还是那些我连名字都记不住的亲戚？
Others whose names I don't even remember?
可如果我饶过了杀害我孙子的凶手
What happens to my dynasty
我的王朝又将如何呢？
if I spare the life of my grandson's killer?
它将由我来延续
It survives through me.
我会解除御林铁卫的职务
I'll leave the Kingsguard.
我会做回你的儿子和继承人
I'll take my place as your son and heir
只要你让提利昂活着
if you let Tyrion live.
成交
Done.
当证人发言完毕 法官们作出有罪判决后
When the testimony's concluded and a guilty verdict rendered,
提利昂将获准发言
Tyrion will be given the chance to speak.
他要乞求开恩 而我会允许他加入守夜人
He'll plead for mercy. I'll allow him to join the Night's Watch.
三天之内 他将被押往黑城堡
In three days' time, he'll depart for Castle Black
并在长城度过余生
and live out his days at the Wall.
而你要立刻脱下白袍
You'll remove your white cloak immediately.
动身离开君临
You will leave King's Landing
前往凯岩城坐上属于你的位置
to assume your rightful place at Casterly Rock.
你要娶一位门当户对的姑娘
You will marry a suitable woman
生下兰尼斯特的孩子
and father children named Lannister.
并永远不再置你的家族于不顾
And you'll never turn your back on your family again.
一言为定
You have my word.
And you have mine.
不怎么顺利 对吧？
Not going well, is it?
- 你会被判有罪 - 噢 你也这么认为？
- You're going to be found guilty. - Oh, you think so?
当你被判罪的时候 你要好好求饶一番
When you are, you need to enter a formal plea for mercy
恳求被发往长城
and ask to be sent to the Wall.
父亲会同意的
Father's agreed to it.
他会饶过你的性命 允许你加入守夜人
He'll spare your life and allow you to join the Night's Watch.
奈德·史塔克之前也这样被允诺过
Ned Stark was promised the same thing
你我都知道他的下场
and we both know how that turned out.
父亲不是乔佛里 他会信守诺言的
Father is not Joffrey. He'll keep his word.
你怎么知道？
How do you know?
你信不信我？
Do you trust me?
把嘴闭上 别再口不择言
Keep your mouth shut. No more outbursts.
这一切很快就会结束
This will all be over soon.
王座将召见下一位证人
The crown may call its next witness.
雪伊
珊莎的侍女 小恶魔的情人
报上名字
State your name.
雪伊
Shae.
你是否以诸神之名
Do you swear by all the gods
起誓所作证言真实而诚实？
that your testimony will be true and honest?
我发誓
I swear it.
你认识这个人吗？
Do you know this man?
认识 提利昂·兰尼斯特
Yes. Tyrion Lannister.
你怎么认识他的？
How do you know him?
我是她夫人珊莎小姐的侍女
I was handmaiden to his wife Lady Sansa.
这个人被控谋杀乔佛里国王
This man stands accused of murdering King Joffrey.
对此你是否知情？
What do you know of this?
据我所知他有罪
I know that he's guilty.
他与珊莎一起密谋
He and Sansa planned it together.
安静！
Silence!
接着说
Continue.
她想为父亲报仇
She wanted revenge for her father,
为她母亲 她哥哥报仇
her mother, her brother.
她将他们的死归咎于国王
She blamed their deaths on the king.
提利昂很高兴能帮她
Tyrion was happy to help.
他恨乔佛里 他恨王后
He hated Joffrey. He hated the queen.
他也恨您 大人
He hated you, my lord.
他从大学士的房间里偷了毒药
He stole poison from the Grand Maester's chamber
放进乔佛里的酒里
to put in Joffrey's wine.
你怎么可能知道这些？
How could you possibly know all this?
他怎么会把自己的计划向他老婆的侍女和盘托出？
Why would he reveal such plans to his wife's maid?
我不仅仅是她的侍女
I wasn't just her maid.
我还是他的妓女
I was his whore.
请再说一遍
I beg your pardon?
你说你是他的……
You said you were his...
他的妓女
His whore.
你怎么跟他勾搭上的？
How did you come to be in his service?
他把我从别人身边抢走
He stole me.
我当时和另一个男人在一起
I was with another man,
那人是大人您的军队里的一位骑士
a knight in your lordship's army.
但提利昂到营地以后
But when Tyrion arrived at the camp,
派了名杀手到我们的帐篷里去
he sent one of his cutthroats into our tent.
他打断了那位骑士的胳膊 把我带到提利昂大人那里去了
He broke the knight's arm and brought me to Lord Tyrion.
“现在你是我的了,” 他这么说
"You belong to me now," he said.
“我要你拿出世界末日的劲头来跟我做爱”
"I want you to fuck me like it's my last night in this world."
安静 安静！
Silence. Silence!
那你有没有呢？
And did you?
我有没有什么？
Did I what?
拿出世界末日的劲头来跟他做爱
Fuck him like it was his last night in this world.
他要的我都照办了
I did everything he wanted.
无论他要我对他做什么
Whatever he told me to do to him.
不管他想对我做什么
Whatever he felt like doing to me.
他要我亲哪里我就亲哪里
I kissed him where he wanted.
他要我舔哪里我就舔哪里
I licked him where he wanted.
他要干哪里我就让他干哪里
I let him put himself where he wanted.
我是他的奴隶
I was his property.
我曾在他房间里一等就是好几个小时
I would wait in his chambers for hours
只为他无聊的时候能享用我
so he could use me when he was bored.
他要我叫他“我的雄狮” 我照办了
He ordered me to call him "my lion," so I did.
我用手捧起他的脸 说道
I took his face in my hands and said,
“我是你的 你是我的”
"I am yours and you are mine."
雪伊
Shae.
求你 别再说了
Please don't.
我是个妓女
I am a whore.
记得吗？
Remember?
那是他跟珊莎成婚之前的事了
That was before he married Sansa.
在那之后 他只想要她
After that, all he wanted was her.
但她不肯让他上床
But she wouldn't let him into her bed.
于是他允诺要为她杀了乔佛里
So he promised to kill King Joffrey for her.
父亲
Father.
我认罪
I wish to confess.
我……认罪
I wish... to confess.
你要认罪？
You wish to confess?
我拯救过你们所有人
I saved you.
我拯救过这座城市
I saved this city
和你们无聊的生命
and all your worthless lives.
我该让史坦尼斯把你们全杀了
I should have let Stannis kill you all.
提利昂
Tyrion.
你要认罪吗？
Do you wish to confess?
是的 父亲
Yes, Father.
我认罪
I'm guilty.
认罪 那不正是你想听到的吗？
Guilty. Is that what you want to hear?
你承认自己毒害国王？
You admit you poisoned the king?
不 关于乔佛里的死我是清白的
No, of that I'm innocent.
我犯的是更为可怕的罪
I'm guilty of a far more monstrous crime.
我的罪是生为侏儒
I am guilty of being a dwarf.
这不是一场对侏儒的审判
You are not on trial for being a dwarf.
噢 当然是了
Oh, yes, I am.
我的人生就是一场对侏儒的审判
I've been on trial for that my entire life.
你没有为自己辩护的吗？
Have you nothing to say in your defense?
除此之外没有别的--
Nothing but this--
我没干过
I did not do it.
我没杀乔佛里
I did not kill Joffrey,
但现在希望是自己干的
but I wish that I had.
看着你那恶毒的小杂种死去
Watching your vicious bastard die
比一千个躺好的妓女都更让我开心
gave me more relief than 1,000 lying whores.
我希望自己真的是你们想象中的怪物
I wish I was the monster you think I am.
我希望自己备下足够的毒药来对付你们所有人
I wish I had enough poison for the whole pack of you.
我会非常开心地看着你们所有人把它咽下去
I would gladly give my life
哪怕赔上自己的性命
to watch you all swallow it.
马林爵士 马林爵士
Ser Meryn. Ser Meryn.
把犯人押回牢房
Escort the prisoner back to his cell.
我不会因乔佛里的死而送掉自己的性命
I will not give my life for Joffrey's murder.
而在这里却得不到正义
And I know I'll get no justice here.
所以我要让上天诸神裁决我的命运
So I will let the gods decide my fate.
我要求比武审判
I demand a trial by combat.
衣柜字幕组出品